

396 Engineering VI, University of California, Los Angeles, CA 90095-1596

□ (+1)310 307 9986 | Zhiyi.zhang@ucla.edu | ★www.zhiyi-zhang.com | ☑ zhiyi-zhang | 🛅 zhiyi-zhang

Summary_

Fifth-year PhD candidate in computer science at UCLA. Experience specializing in System Security in Network Protocols, Data Engineering, Internet of Things, and Information-centric Network. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools.

Education

UCLA Los Angeles, CA, U.S.

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Supervised by Professor Lixia Zhang in the Internet Research Laboratory.
- Research fields: Network Security, Internet of Things, Information-centric Network
- Teaching Assistant of Graduate Course: Internet Architecture and Protocols
- Teaching Assistant of Undergraduate Courses: Software Construction, Computer Network

Nankai Univ. Tianjin, China

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

- Graduated with distinction: Outstanding Graduate Student Award in 2016
- The National Scholarship of China in 2015
- Earned GPA of 3.8/4.0

Experience _____

Internet Research Laboratory, UCLA

Los Angeles, CA, U.S.

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2016

Sep. 2016 - Exp. Jun. 2021

DOCTORAL RESEARCHER

Sep. 2016 - PRESENT

- Project lead of NDN-Lite, a NDN-based IoT Framework which enables user's local control of smart home systems.
- Project lead of El PASSO, a privacy-preserving and asynchronous Single Sign-on protocol with randomizable signature and zero-knowledge proof.
- A Personally Identifiable Information(PII) sharing system with **reliable leaking source identification**.
- Project lead for the design and development of a blockchain-based distributed ledger system to provide security solutions for mesh rooftop solar networking and power grid networking.
- Designed and implemented a NDN-based **DDoS defense** system to mitigate DDoS attacks.
- Research and Development for Access Control Scheme and Certificate Management over NDN.

Transport Security team, Facebook

(Remote) Menlo Park, CA, U.S.

DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIP

- Implemented the first-ever **TLS Batch Signature** in Fizz library for TLS 1.3 to boost TLS performance.
- Finishing a set of benchmark tools in Facebook Fizz library for TLS 1.3 benchmarking.
- Adding new features including Merkle Tree and NSS Key Log into Facebook Fizz library.

Infrastructure Service (AIS) team, Alibaba

Bellevue, WA, U.S.

Jun. 2020 - Sep. 2020

RESEARCH&DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIP

Jun. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- Building high-performance user-mode network stack by adjusting QUIC to work with kernel bypass (DPDK)
- Evaluation of QUIC+DPDK's performance compared with TCP+TLS+HTTP/2 and DPDK+TCP+TLS+HTTP/2
- Explored new congestion control protocol (BBR) in data center network scenario

Honors & Awards _____

2020	Spark Univ. Hackathon Filecoin 2nd Award out of 260 teams , Amount 1k£, Filecoin Pricing Mechanism	Worldwide
2019	UCLA Graduate Division Award, Amount 15k\$, NONRES TUITION GRANT for 2019-2020 academic year.	Los Aneles, U.S.
2018	ACM ICN 2018 Best Poster Award, NDNoT: A Framework for Named Data Network of Things	Boston, U.S.
2016	Outstanding Graduate Student Award, 4 out of 99 in Software Engineering Department, Nankai University	Tianjin, China
2015	The National Scholarship of China, 0.2% undergraduates nationwide, Chinese Department of Education	Tianjin, China
2015	UCLA CSST Scholarship, Amount 7k\$, Cross-Disciplinary Scholars in Science and Technology, UCLA	Los Angeles, U.S.
2015	Honorable Mention Award, Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM)	Tianjin, China

JANUARY 8, 2021 ZHIYI ZHANG · RÉSUMÉ 1



Programming languages C++; C; Python; WebAssembly

Professional Network Security; Internet of Things; Information-centric Network;